Guide to the Lyman Hotchkiss Bagg Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lyman Hotchkiss Bagg papers
1828-1907
MS 849
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.6
Correspondence, manuscripts, and other papers largely relating to Lyman Hotchkiss Bagg's interest in boating; his editorship of the Yale Literary Magazine, 1868-1869; and his weekly "College Chronicle" written for the New York World, 1876-1882. Also included are student translations from Latin and Greek, and correspondence and memorabilia from his years at Yale College, 1865-1869.
Bagg, Lyman Hotchkiss, 1846-1911
Biographical / Historical
Lyman Hotchkiss Bagg: author, journalist; editor of Yale Literary Magazine, 1868-1869, and of the College Courant (New Haven), 1870-1871; wrote weekly "College Chronicle" for the New York World, 1876-1882; author of numerous books.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, manuscripts, and other papers largely relating to Lyman Hotchkiss Bagg's interest in boating; his editorship of the Yale Literary Magazine, 1868-1869; and his weekly "College Chronicle" written for the New York World, 1876-1882. Also included are student translations from Latin and Greek, and correspondence and memorabilia from his years at Yale College, 1865-1869.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Yale Literary Magazine; Students; Authors; Bagg, Lyman Hotchkiss, 1846-1911; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1869; Yale University -- Sports -- Rowing; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Boating letters, 1872-1873 (Box 1)
  - Delta Kappa writings, 1865-1866 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions of college societies, 1866-1868 (Box 1)
  - Easthampton writings, 1863-1865 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous articles written at Easthampton, Massachusetts, 1863-1865 (Box 1)
  - Letters received by the Yale Literary Magazine, 1868 May-1869 June (Box 1)
  - Letters to Edwin Oviatt, 1907 (Box 1)
  - Letter to E. H. Lewis, 1907 January 7 (Box 1)
  - Adelphi scrawls, 1863-1865 (Box 2)
  - Boating letters, 1871, undated (Box 2)
  - Postcards, miscellaneous papers, [ca. 1871-1892] (Box 2)
  - "Four Years at Yale", 1871 (Box 3)
  - Boating articles, 1872-1883 (Box 3)
  - Letters to Lyman H. Bagg, [ca. 1880-1895] (Box 3)
  - Letters to Lyman H. Bagg (cont'd), [ca. 1880-1895] (Box 3A)
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 3A)
  - Bound volume: "Translations from the Latin.. Yale College 1865-1868" (Box 4)
  - Bound volume: "Translations from the Greek... Yale College 1865-1868" (Box 4)
  - Clippings from The World, [ca. 1828-1891] (Box 5)
  - Papers related to the "College Chronicle," The World, [1877-1882?] (Box 5)
  - Bibliography cards, undated (Box 6)